<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Jessica Jagdeo ESM 244 Blog</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Jessica Jagdeo ESM 244 Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Santa Ynez River Water Quality</title>
      <link>/blog/1/01/01/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/1/01/01/project3/</guid>
      <description>The quality of water within a watershed affects people who rely on surficial water for drinking, as well as the local wildlife. The Santa Ynez River flows into the Gibraltar Reservoir and Lake Cachuma and water is diverted from these reservoirs to nearby cities. The Santa Ynez Watershed supplies water to residents within the City of Santa Barbara, Goleta, Montecito, and other towns. Since 1998, water quality measurements have been taken along the Santa Ynez River.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonanza Creek Snowshow Hare Examination</title>
      <link>/blog/1/01/01/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/1/01/01/project1/</guid>
      <description>From 1999 to 2017, physical characteristics of snowshoe hares were observed and recorded in the Bonanza Creek Experimental Forest within Alaska (Kielland et al. 2017). This project utilizes the data obtained from this study to visualize the weight and sex of the observed snowshoe hares. In addition, this project explores the summary statistics of the recorded weights for both female and male snowshoe hares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Runoff Ratio in Santa Cruz Creek Sub-basin</title>
      <link>/blog/1/01/01/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/1/01/01/project4/</guid>
      <description>To understand the hydrological processes specific to a particular watershed, it is important to understand how much runoff is generated within the area. The runoff ratio for a particular watershed can be calculated if there are good records of precipitation and discharge within the watershed. In the Santa Ynez Watershed, Santa Barbara County maintains a record of precipitation at Lake Cachuma and the US Geological Survey records discharge at the Santa Cruz sub-basin, which is near Lake Cachuma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gibraltar Reservoir Capacity</title>
      <link>/blog/1/01/01/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/1/01/01/project2/</guid>
      <description>Construction of Gibraltar Reservoir finished in 1920. The capacity of the reservoir was supposed to be slightly over 20,000 acre-feet, but sedimentation had already reduced the water storage capacity of the reservoir to about 15,000 acre-feet. Since 1920, Gibraltar has faced issues from sedimentation. In 1949, the City of Santa Barbara had to raise Gibraltar Dam due to the amount of sediment accumulating within its confines. Raising the dam maintained the water storage capacity of about 15,000 acre-feet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>